# Freddie Brown

mail@freddie.io

#### **Personal Statement**

Undergraduate computer scientist, going into second year, studying at Southampton University with significant experience developing highly-reliable commercial software. I thrive on learning and finding solutions to problems using technology, and have significant experience working in software engineering teams effectively.

# **Previous Experience**

FiveAI Bristol

Software Engineering Intern (Paid)

September 2017 - September 2018

Responsible for the in-car visualisations that displayed sensor and car compute data in real-time, as well as working with ROS (Robot Operating System), C++ and Python to create nodes that manipulated camera data in real-time. The visualisation ran on a tablet with low compute specifications, so required an efficient rendering engine that used WebGL. Refined loose specifications to detailed technical specifications before starting the projects, and worked closely with multiple other developers in a scrum team.

Foresight Southampton

Technical Co-founder December 2017 - Present

Built an iOS app for virtual stock trading (currently in Beta) users bet on stocks and cryptocurrencies without high commission fees, allowing users to understand the stock market and hone their skills safely. My co-founder and I have raised a €12,000 pre-seed round to speed up our pursuit of product-market-fit. We were also selected for Y Combinator Startup School, an online accelerator with a mentorship from a Silicon Valley startup CEO. I manage two freelancers who work on a part-time basis, and we use a Jira scrum board for project management.

### Scan & Share (myphotoscanning.co.uk)

Stratford-upon-Avon

Founder

January 2008 - Present

Developed the concept of photograph, slide and negative scanning service from start up to ongoing revenue generation, employing several family members. Many skills have been used and developed - market analysis, strategy, initial web design, v2 web specification and launch, digital marketing (including SEO), product development, accounting, customer service, team management and time management.

Gamma Labs Stratford-upon-Avon

Website Developer 2016

Following success with online corporate design competitions, Gamma Labs was established to handle web design contracts for companies including Razor Secure and Feonic Vibration Technology. This involved working closely with clients to define a specification that encapsulated their vision and then executing on that specification to specific deadlines.

### **Education**

Southampton University Southampton

BSc Computer Science (Modules: Programming I - 78%, Foundations of CS - 54%, Computer Systems - 73%, Professional Development - 77%)

2018-2021

King Edward VI School

A/AS levels: Computer Science (A\*), Maths (A), Physics (B), Chemistry AS (A)

Stratford-upon-Avon

2015-2017

St. Benedict's High School

Alcester

12 GCSEs, 4 A\*s and 8 As 2013-2015

# **Personal Experience**

#### **Arkwright Engineering Scholarship**

2015

Awarded a sixth-form scholarship for my computer science and electronics engineering projects. I have been sponsored by National Grid, who also acted as a mentor for two years.

#### **Business and Innovation Award from Pure Potential**

2015

Awarded by Pure Potential, supported by EY, for creating Scan & Share and growing it into one of the leading UK photo scanning services.

# **Young Founders Second Cohort**

2016

I was selected and took part in a two-week enterprise education programme for 16-18 year olds which expanded my entrepreneurial skill-set. Over the fortnight, I took an early stage idea and developed it through to a business that I pitched to several leading entrepreneurs and VCs.

#### Hackathons

- HackTheHolidays (*Dec 2016*) 2nd place Built an online Christmas cracker game using the HTML5 acceleration APIs.
- HackTrain 3.0 (Nov 2016) Built a widget for iOS that allows train passengers to view cellular network availability along a route
- HackTheMidlands (Oct 2016) Built an image sharing application that used Estimote beacons.
- HackTheHolidays (Dec 2015) 1st place Built software to display the results of an online poll on Christmas tree LEDs.

#### Silver and Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Awards

2013-2016

Currently completing my Gold DofE award, as part of the programme, I have been volunteering for 12 months with the Stratford-upon-Avon Foodbank.

## **Technical and Personal Skills**

### Technical Expertise:

Proficient in: JavaScript (specifically with NodeJS, React and Angular frameworks), C++ (especially with ROS and LibAV), Python (especially with ROS), HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Swift, Objective-C, MongoDB Also basic ability with: Java, C, Bash.

#### • Software Skills:

Git (including GitHub and Gitlab), Docker, Debian-based OS distributions, MacOS, XCode, Eclipse, VSCode, Atom, Adobe Illustrator, Sketch, Invision, Jira.

#### • General Business Skills:

Good efficiency, strong work-ethic and understands how to deliver a complete solution to a problem. Team work skills, especially in an agile/scrum environment.